Submarines
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Submarines, 2.1.3.1.3.1
  - Submarines: Submarines, circa 1914 - 1918; 4 (Box 1511)
    - [GERMAN U BOAT ARRIVES IN AMERICA LANDING AT NEWPORT R.I. PHOTOGRAPH BY INTERNATIONAL FILM SERVICE. The Capta in and crew lined upon the deck of the German U Boat 53 in Newport harbor. Immediately after her arrival the craft was surrounded by hundreds of motor boats, the occupatns cheering the intrepid sailors.], 16
    - Verso: GERMAN U BOAT ARRIVES IN AMERICA LANDING AT NEWPORT R.I. PHOTOGRAPH BY INTERNATIONAL FILM SERVICE. The Capta in and crew lined upon the deck of the German U Boat 53 in Newport harbor. Immediately after her arrival the craft was surrounded by hundreds of motor boats, the occupatns cheering the intrepid sailors., 16-verso
    - [IN A BRITISH SUBMERSIBLE Commander of a British submarine watching thru the periscope of the vessel, the surface of the eater for the approach of enemy craft. Great Britain is combating the German menace with her own submersibles and while it is like 'tracing a needle in a haystack" to fight submarines with submarine, still results so far obtained have been highly satisfactory.], 17
    - Verso: IN A BRITISH SUBMERSIBLE Commander of a British submarine watching thru the periscope of the vessel, the surface of the eater for the approach of enemy craft. Great Britain is combating the German menace with her own submersibles and while it is like 'tracing a needle in a haystack" to fight submarines with submarine, still results so far obtained have been highly satisfactory., 17-verso
    - [Gun crew on board ready to repel an attack], 18
    - Verso: Gun crew on board ready to repel an attack, 18-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 2 Cleaning of deck gun of U-35 during good weather. ], 19
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 2 Cleaning of deck gun of U-35 during good weather., 19-verso
    - [From Part 6 Reel 3 The "Maplewood" Ship sunk by U-35.], 20
    - Verso: From Part 6 Reel 3 The "Maplewood" Ship sunk by U-35., 20-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 1 "Maplewood" After the steamship's crew was safe, the ship was destroyed by a torpedo.], 21
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 1 "Maplewood" After the steamship's crew was safe, the ship was destroyed by a torpedo., 21-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 1 U-35 sinks the "Maplewood"], 22
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 1 U-35 sinks the "Maplewood", 22-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 1 "Maplewood" set 98-A (A to F) "Maplewood" 3239 tons with 5175 tons (Eisenerz(?)) iron ore, England], 23
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 1 "Maplewood" set 98-A (A to F) "Maplewood" 3239 tons with 5175 tons (Eisenerz[?]) iron ore, England, 23-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 1 "Maplewood" is sunk by U-35.], 24
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 1 "Maplewood" is sunk by U-35., 24-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 1 Film of Sinking of "Maplewood" too bad to secure prints "Maplewood" has been hit in this scene. Caption states that ship sank in two minutes.], 25
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 1 Film of Sinking of "Maplewood" too bad to secure prints "Maplewood" has been hit in this scene. Caption states that ship sank in two minutes., 25-verso
    - [Part 5-Reel 2 of U-35 The armed Italian steamer "Stromboli" 5466 tons, cargo 1200 tons of steel, iron, nickel and barbed wire for Italian War Ministry. Bound from Baltimore to Genoa, crew allowed to leave ship before sinking.], 26
    - Verso: Part 5-Reel 2 of U-35 The armed Italian steamer "Stromboli" 5466 tons, cargo 1200 tons of steel, iron, nickel and barbed wire for Italian War Ministry. Bound from Baltimore to Genoa, crew allowed to leave ship before sinking., 26-verso
    - [Part 7 Reel 2 freighter sunk by U-35. Subsequent scenes show sunset off Algiers The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli."], 27
    - Verso: Part 7 Reel 2 freighter sunk by U-35. Subsequent scenes show sunset off Algiers The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli.", 27-verso
    - [Part 7 Reel 2 Steamship sunk by U-35 The armed Italian steamer "Stromboli."], 28
    - Verso: Part 7 Reel 2 Steamship sunk by U-35 The armed Italian steamer "Stromboli.", 28-verso
    - [Part 7 Reel 2 Steamship sunk by U-35 Subsequent scenes show sunset off Algiers. The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli"], 29
    - Verso: Part 7 Reel 2 Steamship sunk by U-35 Subsequent scenes show sunset off Algiers. The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli", 29-verso
    - [Part 7 Reel 2 Steamship sunk by U-35 The armed Italian steamer "Stromboli."], 30
    - Verso: Part 7 Reel 2 Steamship sunk by U-35 The armed Italian steamer "Stromboli.", 30-verso
    - [Part 7 Reel 2 Steamship sunk by U-35 Italian steamship "Stromboli"], 31
    - Verso: Part 7 Reel 2 Steamship sunk by U-35 Italian steamship "Stromboli", 31-verso
    - [Part 7 Reel 2 - sunk by U-35 The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli" of 5466 tons, cargo 1200 tons of steel, iron, nickel and barbed wire for the Italian War Ministry. Bound from Baltimore to Genoa. The crew of the captured ship is allowed to leave before it is sunk. ], 32
    - Verso: Part 7 Reel 2 - sunk by U-35 The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli" of 5466 tons, cargo 1200 tons of steel, iron, nickel and barbed wire for the Italian War Ministry. Bound from Baltimore to Genoa. The crew of the captured ship is allowed to leave before it is sunk., 32-verso
    - [Part 5 Reel 2, of U-35 film record The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli" of 5466 tons, cargo 1200 tons of steel, iron, nickel and barbed wire for the Italian War Ministry is captured. Bound from Baltimore to Genoa. The crew is allowed to leave the ship.], 33
    - Verso: Part 5 Reel 2, of U-35 film record The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli" of 5466 tons, cargo 1200 tons of steel, iron, nickel and barbed wire for the Italian War Ministry is captured. Bound from Baltimore to Genoa. The crew is allowed to leave the ship., 33-verso
    - [U-35 Italian steamship "Stromboli"], 34
    - Verso: U-35 Italian steamship "Stromboli", 34-verso
    - [ From Film Record of German Submarine U-35 Italian steamship "Stromboli", 35
    - Verso: From Film Record of German Submarine U-35 Italian steamship "Stromboli", 35-verso
    - [From film record of U-35 The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli"], 36
    - Verso: From film record of U-35 The armed Italian steamship "Stromboli", 36-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 1 U-35 sinks the "Maplewood" 3239 tons cargo: iron ore], 37
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 1 U-35 sinks the "Maplewood" 3239 tons cargo: iron ore, 37-verso
    - [Part 4 Reel 1 U-35 sinks the "Maplewood"], 38
    - Verso: Part 4 Reel 1 U-35 sinks the "Maplewood", 38-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 1], 39
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 1, 39-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 1], 40
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 1, 40-verso
  - Submarines: Submarines, circa 1914 - 1918; 5 (Box 1511)
    - [Germans naval North Sea the submarines in (?)], 1
    - Verso: Germans naval North Sea the submarines in [?], 1-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 3 Deck gun of U-35 in action shooting at the English steamer "Korfu"], 2
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 3 Deck gun of U-35 in action shooting at the English steamer "Korfu", 2-verso
    - [Part 1 Reel 2 The commander of the U-35 sets the course and the helmsman shoots the sun to find the position of the U-boat.], 3
    - Verso: Part 1 Reel 2 The commander of the U-35 sets the course and the helmsman shoots the sun to find the position of the U-boat., 3-verso
    - [This is Captain Albert Gayer[?], chief at one time of the U-boat flotilla at Emden. (Picture given me by Zentner.)], 4
    - Verso: This is Captain Albert Gayer[?], chief at one time of the U-boat flotilla at Emden. (Picture given me by Zentner.), 4-verso
    - [U B type of submarine. Saw at front for cutting through nets], 5
    - Verso: U B type of submarine. Saw at front for cutting through nets, 5-verso
    - [The U-93 (von Spiegel)], 6
    - Verso: The U-93 (von Spiegel), 6-verso
    - [U.S.S. Illnois being sunk by German submarine], 7
    - Verso: U.S.S. Illnois being sunk by German submarine, 7-verso
    - [Wrestling match on U 140], 8
    - Verso: Wrestling match on U 140, 8-verso
    - [Das Handels u-boot, welches wahrend des Krieges(?) - ...], 9
    - Verso: Das Handels u-boot, welches wahrend des Krieges[?] - ..., 9-verso
    - [The commander of U-93 has refreshment on top of conning tower (von Spiegel)], 10
    - Verso: The commander of U-93 has refreshment on top of conning tower (von Spiegel), 10-verso
    - [The submarine cruiser U 140-biggest submarine the Germans had. - biggest in world (Kophamel)], 11
    - Verso: The submarine cruiser U 140-biggest submarine the Germans had. - biggest in world (Kophamel), 11-verso
    - [Von Arnauld de la Peru[?] the German U-Boat ace crossing the North S...], 12
    - Verso: Von Arnauld de la Peru[?] the German U-Boat ace crossing the North S..., 12-verso
    - [S.S. (?), a Norwegian sailing ship sunk in 1918 by the U-151], 13
    - Verso: S.S. [?], a Norwegian sailing ship sunk in 1918 by the U-151, 13-verso
    - [French battleship Danton largest war vessel sunk by torpedo during war. sunk by U 64 Mar 19/17], 14
    - Verso: French battleship Danton largest war vessel sunk by torpedo during war. sunk by U 64 Mar 19/17, 14-verso
    - [usual black and white finishing line], 15
    - Verso: usual black and white finishing line, 15-verso
    - [On U 35 Scanning the sea for prospects from top of conning tower.], 16
    - Verso: On U 35 Scanning the sea for prospects from top of conning tower., 16-verso
    - [U-93 leaving on first trip. Prince Henry of Prussia on board. The commander, Baron von Spiegel just behind the prince.], 17
    - Verso: U-93 leaving on first trip. Prince Henry of Prussia on board. The commander, Baron von Spiegel just behind the prince., 17-verso
    - [U-35 running into Cartagena (von Arnauld story)], 18
    - Verso: U-35 running into Cartagena (von Arnauld story), 18-verso
    - [Crew of U-35 on shore at Cartagena + crowd watching the U-boat.], 19
    - Verso: Crew of U-35 on shore at Cartagena + crowd watching the U-boat., 19-verso
    - [Scene at Cape Hellas, showing (in center of picture) the overturned hull of British battleship Majestic, sunk by Heising(?) in U21.], 20
    - Verso: Scene at Cape Hellas, showing (in center of picture) the overturned hull of British battleship Majestic, sunk by Heising[?] in U21., 20-verso
    - [getting a torpedo on board a submarine], 21
    - Verso: getting a torpedo on board a submarine, 21-verso
    - [This is Oaf Weddigen of U-9, who sank the three British warships "Hogue" "Cressy" + "Aboukir"], 22
    - Verso: This is Oaf Weddigen of U-9, who sank the three British warships "Hogue" "Cressy" + "Aboukir", 22-verso
    - [Berlin, May 5, 1929. Dear Mr. Thomas :- Spending a nice evening together at my home, we have resolved to send you this sign of our remembrance. I trust you will let me know whenever you come across. Very sincerely yours, Robert Motaht[?], Top U-boat Capt. P.S. in the meantime we'll drink a little schnaps to your health Josephine Lehman], 23
    - Verso: Berlin, May 5, 1929. Dear Mr. Thomas :- Spending a nice evening together at my home, we have resolved to send you this sign of our remembrance. I trust you will let me know whenever you come across. Very sincerely yours, Robert Motaht[?], Top U-boat Capt. P.S. in the meantime we'll drink a little schnaps to your health Josephine Lehman, 23-verso
    - [his is in the little village where Comm. Hersing lives. The old tower dates from the 12th century.], 24
    - Verso: This is in the little village where Comm. Hersing lives. The old tower dates from the 12th century., 24-verso
    - [One of Von Spiegel's pictures], 25
    - Verso: One of Von Spiegel's pictures, 25-verso
    - [This is a UB-boat type, smaller than the regular U-boats. In the back ground are the cliffs of Helgaland. Notice the saw at the bow for cutting through nets. This picture might be used with the Hashagen story, as he was at one time on the UB 21. This one is twice as large, however.], 26
    - Verso: This is a UB-boat type, smaller than the regular U-boats. In the back ground are the cliffs of Helgaland. Notice the saw at the bow for cutting through nets. This picture might be used with the Hashagen story, as he was at one time on the UB 21. This one is twice as large, however., 26-verso
    - [Shower bath on deck of a submarine U-35.], 27
    - Verso: Shower bath on deck of a submarine U-35., 27-verso
    - [Picture of walled docks], 28
    - [British Q ship Tulip sunk by Com. Hashagen in U62.], 29
    - Verso: British Q ship Tulip sunk by Com. Hashagen in U62., 29-verso
    - [Comm. Johannes Klasing lost with U34 on Nov 9, 1918, when U-boats were making last trip from Austun(?) to Germany. This was the last U-boat destroyed by the Allies before the Armstrice. He was destroyed by depth charges from Q ship "Rivel."], 30
    - Verso: Comm. Johannes Klasing lost with U34 on Nov 9, 1918, when U-boats were making last trip from Austun[?] to Germany. This was the last U-boat destroyed by the Allies before the Armstrice. He was destroyed by depth charges from Q ship "Rivel.", 30-verso
    - [3 Polish block ships - Intrepid, Ophigenia(?), + Thetis blocking submarine outlet at Zeebrugge], 31
    - Verso: 3 Polish block ships - Intrepid, Ophigenia[?], + Thetis blocking submarine outlet at Zeebrugge, 31-verso
    - [Two men standing in shade underneath airplane], 32
    - [To be returned to WG Cleaver], 33
    - Verso: To be returned to WG Cleaver, 33-verso
    - [HMS Viedielive(?) in Dover harbour after raid on Zeebrugge], 34
    - Verso: HMS Viedielive[?] in Dover harbour after raid on Zeebrugge, 34-verso
    - [Took from the stern of the Submarine D8 Captain Brodie + myself on bridge Return to William Gladstone Cleaver.], 35
    - Verso: Took from the stern of the Submarine D8 Captain Brodie + myself on bridge Return to William Gladstone Cleaver., 35-verso
    - [Some of Crew of U 64 Com. Moraht in background], 36
    - Verso: Some of Crew of U 64 Com. Moraht in background, 36-verso
  - Submarines: Submarines, circa 1914 - 1918; 6 (Box 1511)
    - [Amiral(?) de Kersaint(?) The Frenchman that put up such good fight Sunk Sept 14/17], 1
    - Verso: Amiral[?] de Kersaint[?] The Frenchman that put up such good fight Sunk Sept 14/17, 1-verso
    - [Sinking a sailing ship after it has been abandoned], 2
    - Verso: Sinking a sailing ship after it has been abandoned, 2-verso
    - [Amiral de Kersaint[?]], 3
    - Verso: Amiral de Kersaint[?], 3-verso
    - [Italian steamer Fert[?] sunk June 6/17 after gunfire battle.], 4
    - Verso: Italian steamer Fert[?] sunk June 6/17 after gunfire battle., 4-verso
    - [Supper on board in the Bay of Cattaro. (This is Moraht's boat, the German U-64)], 5
    - Verso: Supper on board in the Bay of Cattaro. (This is Moraht's boat, the German U-64), 5-verso
    - [U117 Camouflage put on off Am. coast for benefit of American flyers.], 6
    - Verso: U117 Camouflage put on off Am. coast for benefit of American flyers., 6-verso
    - [Officers U-35 Spring 1916 Left to right: Eng. Lt. Fechter Comm. Von Arnauld Lt. Steinbauer + Lt. Lauenburg], 7
    - Verso: Officers U-35 Spring 1916 Left to right: Eng. Lt. Fechter Comm. Von Arnauld Lt. Steinbauer + Lt. Lauenburg, 7-verso
    - [Large group of sailors posing on deck of ship], 8
    - Verso: Officers, left to right: Lt. Lauenburg, Lt. Obenmuller, Lt. Steinbauer von Arnold? [many more handwritten notes], 8-verso
    - [Caption: Periskop eine Unterseebootes], 9
    - [Shower bath on board U-64], 10
    - Verso: Shower bath on board U-64, 10-verso
    - [U-64 able seaman Fistle[?] sitting on the masthead When steamers scaice[?] a sailor at aloft scanning horizon], 11
    - Verso: U-64 able seaman Fistle[?] sitting on the masthead When steamers scaice[?] a sailor at aloft scanning horizon, 11-verso
    - [One of the sailing ships sunk.], 12
    - Verso: One of the sailing ships sunk., 12-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 1], 13
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 1, 13-verso
    - [Caption: The Mole at Zeebrugge before attack], 14
    - [Caption: GOING DOWN Sunk by von Arnauld aboard the U-35], 15
    - [A U-boat of the same type as the U-64], 16
    - Verso: A U-boat of the same type as the U-64, 16-verso
    - [Bathing in the Atlantic on U-35], 17
    - Verso: Bathing in the Atlantic on U-35, 17-verso
    - [The U-35], 18
    - Verso: The U-35, 18-verso
    - [Part 2 Reel 2 Cleaning of deck gun of U-35 during good weather. ], 19
    - Verso: Part 2 Reel 2 Cleaning of deck gun of U-35 during good weather., 19-verso
    - [Commander of U-35 writes[?] a radio message Commander Von Arnauld], 20
    - Verso: Commander of U-35 writes[?] a radio message Commander Von Arnauld, 20-verso
    - [Near end of Reel 3 - Part of crew on deck of U-35 at sunset.], 21
    - Verso: Near end of Reel 3 - Part of crew on deck of U-35 at sunset., 21-verso
    - [Bathing in the Atlantic aboard the U-35], 22
    - Verso: Bathing in the Atlantic aboard the U-35, 22-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 1 No 81-F (F and G shows hit and growing smoke from explosion)], 23
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 1 No 81-F (F and G shows hit and growing smoke from explosion), 23-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 1 No 81-G (See F, where ship is hit)], 24
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 1 No 81-G (See F, where ship is hit), 24-verso
    - [Part 3 Reel 1], 25
    - Verso: Part 3 Reel 1, 25-verso
    - [Deck gun of the U-35 in action. A heavy sea washes gunners' feet.], 26
    - Verso: Deck gun of the U-35 in action. A heavy sea washes gunners' feet., 26-verso
    - [Deck gun of U-35 shooting at Nentmore], 27
    - Verso: Deck gun of U-35 shooting at Nentmore, 27-verso
    - [Aerial view of ship at sea carrying large amount of cargo], 28
    - [A Whitehead Torpedo 18" dia x 16' long. It is itself a screw propelled submarine, driven by compressed air + guided by an automatic steering device controlled by a gyroscope. It travels at 29 to 30 knots + is effective at 2000 yds.], 29
    - Verso: A Whitehead Torpedo 18" dia x 16' long. It is itself a screw propelled submarine, driven by compressed air + guided by an automatic steering device controlled by a gyroscope. It travels at 29 to 30 knots + is effective at 2000 yds., 29-verso
  - Submarines: U-boats, circa 1914 - 1918; 7 (Box 1511)
    - [The U -"Deutschland"- U155 - lying alongside Q ship Suffolk Coast (Auten) in London docks after the Armstice], 1
    - Verso: The U -"Deutschland"- U155 - lying alongside Q ship Suffolk Coast (Auten) in London docks after the Armstice, 1-verso
    - [Making his wartime fishnets: Old fisherman wiring together glass floats on nets to catch subs.], 2
    - Verso: Making his wartime fishnets: Old fisherman wiring together glass floats on nets to catch subs., 2-verso
    - Note: 4 - pictures of some ship in her various disguises; 2 - of her tricky deck house + funnel; 1 - her commander disguised as a commercial traveller; 1 - rescued crew; 1 - the [illegible] mystery ship Commander Godfrey Herbert disguised as a Dutch captain., 3
    - [Passing the sweep between two minesweepers], 4
    - Verso: Passing the sweep between two minesweepers, 4-verso
    - [Listening for submarines on a trawler with hydrophone], 5
    - Verso: Listening for submarines on a trawler with hydrophone, 5-verso
    - [British drifter fleet flying the white ensign of war], 6
    - Verso: British drifter fleet flying the white ensign of war, 6-verso
    - [British submarine ward room. Man at left making tea], 7
    - Verso: British submarine ward room. Man at left making tea, 7-verso
    - [Mine laying submarine. A UC-boat], 8
    - Verso: Mine laying submarine. A UC-boat, 8-verso
    - [Typical fishermen on a fishing smach(?)], 9
    - Verso: Typical fishermen on a fishing smach(?), 9-verso
    - [Oil on water after sinking German submarine], 10
    - Verso: Oil on water after sinking German submarine, 10-verso
    - [The U-20 which sails(?) the 'Lusitania'], 11
    - Verso: The U-20 which sails(?) the 'Lusitania', 11-verso
    - [Gordon Campbell and his paymaster. Capmbell was the British mystery(?) ship ace of aces], 12
    - Verso: Gordon Campbell and his paymaster. Capmbell was the British mystery(?) ship ace of aces, 12-verso
    - [Gordon Campbell on ship "Farmborough"(?) beached at Berehaven after fight with U-boat, in which U-boat was sunk], 13
    - Verso: Gordon Campbell on ship "Farmborough"(?) beached at Berehaven after fight with U-boat, in which U-boat was sunk, 13-verso
    - [Fourth disguise on ship Baranea(?) - side alleyways closed up, hull and ships boats repainted], 14
    - Verso: Fourth disguise on ship Baranea(?) - side alleyways closed up, hull and ships boats repainted, 14-verso
    - [Gordon Campbell's ship, Famrborough(?) beached at Berehaven(?) after being badley wrecked and when it fought and sank a U-boat], 15
    - Verso: Gordon Campbell's ship, Famrborough(?) beached at Berehaven(?) after being badley wrecked and when it fought and sank a U-boat, 15-verso
    - [Dummy deckhouse of ship Barraner(?) with dummy wheels to highlight the roof raises and sides drop away to disclose guns], 16
    - Verso: Dummy deckhouse of ship Barraner(?) with dummy wheels to highlight the roof raises and sides drop away to disclose guns, 16-verso
    - [no description], 17
    - Verso, 17-verso
    - [The Barranca(?), in her original colour as a West Indian fruit(?) ship...], 18
    - Verso: The Barranca(?), in her original colour as a West Indian fruit(?) ship..., 18-verso
    - [On ship Barranca(?), with yellow funnel with black top], 19
    - Verso: On ship Barranca(?), with yellow funnel with black top, 19-verso
    - [Crew of torpedoed steamer rescued by the Barranca(?) - (Commander Douglas)], 20
    - Verso: Crew of torpedoed steamer rescued by the Barranca(?) - (Commander Douglas), 20-verso
    - [Painting the funnel of the ship Barranca(?)], 21
    - Verso: Painting the funnel of the ship Barranca(?), 21-verso
    - [Commander S.C. Douglas on his ship, wearing false mustache and masquerading as commercial traveller], 22
    - Verso: Commander S.C. Douglas on his ship, wearing false mustache and masquerading as commercial traveller, 22-verso
    - [Commander Godfrey Herbert as a Dutch person(?) on his ship, the Antwerp], 23
    - Verso: Commander Godfrey Herbert as a Dutch person(?) on his ship, the Antwerp, 23-verso
    - [Muptery(?) ship crew - same one- is guised(?) as crew of Mereband(?) vessel], 24
    - Verso: Muptery(?) ship crew - same one- is guised(?) as crew of Mereband(?) vessel, 24-verso
    - [British trawlers crew. On the trip on which this picture was taken, the wireless cabin was later blown away by a 4inch shell from a U-boat], 25
    - Verso: British trawlers crew. On the trip on which this picture was taken, the wireless cabin was later blown away by a 4inch shell from a U-boat, 25-verso
    - [Mystery (?) of ship crew in service uniform], 26
    - Verso: Mystery (?) of ship crew in service uniform, 26-verso
    - [British steam travelers(?) and drifters in Dooer harbour], 27
    - Verso: British steam travelers(?) and drifters in Dooer harbour, 27-verso
    - [A traveler(?) that hit a mine], 28
    - Verso: A traveler(?) that hit a mine, 28-verso
    - [Officers and crew of Polish minesweeper, St. Seirol], 29
    - Verso: Officers and crew of Polish minesweeper, St. Seirol, 29-verso
    - [Firing at mines with rifles to explode them], 30
    - Verso: Firing at mines with rifles to explode them, 30-verso
    - [Periscope!], 31
    - Verso: Periscope!, 31-verso
    - [Comm. Harold Auter(?), ship captain], 32
    - Verso: Comm. Harold Auter(?), ship captain, 32-verso
    - [One of the most pretentious(?) against the submarine...], 33
    - Verso: One of the most pretentious (?) against the submarine, 33-verso
    - [Comm. Harold Auter(?) and his ship crew], 34
    - Verso: Comm. Harold Auter(?) and his ship crew, 34-verso
  Box 1512
- Submarines, 2.1.3.1.3.1
  - Submarines: Max Valentiner - family photos, circa 1880s - 1930s; 1 (Box 1512)